<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>initialed85's misc tech stuff</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/</link><description>Recent content on initialed85's misc tech stuff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:53:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://initialed85.cc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quake on WASM With WebSocket multiplayer</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/quake-on-wasm-with-websocket-multiplayer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:53:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/quake-on-wasm-with-websocket-multiplayer/</guid><description>Genesis When I was a kid, my dad taught computing / programming at Alanvale TAFE; he would often bring home old computers from work (I think when they upgraded their machines) and network them together, so we always had computers around the house and I was interested in them from an early age.
The first vivid nightmare I remember was when my older sister let me play a bit of Wolfenstein 3D and I guess it was on her save game where you confront Hitler.</description></item><item><title>Software vs Lego</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/software-vs-lego/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 17:16:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/software-vs-lego/</guid><description>My son August (Augie to us, he&amp;rsquo;s almost 4) has always loved Lego (well, Duplo).
For the longest time he&amp;rsquo;d build really long rectangular trucks, he seemed to like getting every block packed in tightly on the tray / trailer(s) of the truck.
Lately though he&amp;rsquo;s started building complicated trucks with lots of different levels and pieces, explaining things like &amp;ldquo;this truck has 3 hotels and a crane and 2 guns&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Cloudy with a chance of vendor lock-in balls</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/cloudy-with-a-chance-of-vendor-lock-in-balls/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 17:38:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/cloudy-with-a-chance-of-vendor-lock-in-balls/</guid><description>I started writing this article before I changed jobs, which was basically 6 months ago (in May 2023).
I&amp;rsquo;m gonna basically leave it as it was and just mark up the parts I got wrong / the parts that turned out differently as an exercise in I dunno, maybe forced humility / embarassment?
So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the article I wrote before I started the new gig and then follow it up with the last 6 months of reality.</description></item><item><title>Recent projects of note</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/recent-projects-of-note/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 20:45:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/recent-projects-of-note/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been finding my job that interesting of late which normally results in me having a lot of energy for my out-of-work pursuits.
Unfortunately for reasons I can&amp;rsquo;t quite work out yet, I also haven&amp;rsquo;t been motivated to make any music and so all that&amp;rsquo;s really left is personal projects.
Anyway- the next few headings cover the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to.
Minecraft I had a bit of time off over Christmas and we all went to stay with my wife&amp;rsquo;s family in Darwin where we enjoyed monsoonal weather and lots of pool time.</description></item><item><title>An update on the Ghettowulf Cluster</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/an-update-on-the-ghettowulf-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 15:49:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/an-update-on-the-ghettowulf-cluster/</guid><description>So it&amp;rsquo;s been about 2 months since I last wrote about this thing and it had been running for a couple of weeks before I wrote about it, which means it&amp;rsquo;s been operating for maybe 3 months all up.
Despite a few initial teething issues, I have to say it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty good (and definitely less maintenance than my old setup was).
Here&amp;rsquo;s how it looks at the moment:
As you can see, cable management is my passion.</description></item><item><title>Permacomputing</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/permacomputing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 21:11:33 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/permacomputing/</guid><description>I stumbled across an article on lobste.rs that spoke about permacomputing which interested me initially because I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of it.
As the website suggests the principles are a good place to start.
In particular the lifespan maximization approach resonated with me, here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt:
Lifespan maximization is the extension of hardware lifespan by the users. It may be supported by planned longevity from the manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s side, but it rarely is.</description></item><item><title>How to write code like a Dinosaur</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/how-to-write-code-like-a-dinosaur/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 12:43:02 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/how-to-write-code-like-a-dinosaur/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a personal project called Dinosaur; it&amp;rsquo;s a single-page application that presents the user with two horizontal panes- a code editor in the language of your choice and a live feed to your code being executed.
Languages presently supported are:
C Go Java Lua Python Rust TypeScript Initially this sounds a bit like any of the various coding games / exercises out there but I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to add what I think is a slight variation in that all user sessions have network stack access to the same network as all other user sessions (in time I&amp;rsquo;ll probably permit this to be broken up into groups, permitting isolated group sessions).</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting a mysterious Python test failure</title><link>https://initialed85.cc/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 20:31:01 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://initialed85.cc/posts/first-post/</guid><description>At my day job my colleagues and I develop a data gathering and visualisation platform that has a fair bit of Python behind the scenes.
We test a lot of this Python using pytest and all our tests are run by a large locally hosted instance of TeamCity.
A test run involves TeamCity executing a bash script responsible for setting up any test dependencies (usually Docker containers) and then executing the test itself (also usually a Docker container).</description></item></channel></rss>